http://www.dma.org.uk/privacy-and-cookie-policy

DMA - Data and Marketing Association
Log in or Register
Email
Password
Forgot Password?
Community
ThemeCustomerCreativityDataInnovationLegalCoronavirusDiversity & InclusionSectorAutomotiveFinancial ServicesFMCGHealthcareNot-For-ProfitRetailTravelTelecommsChannelExperientialEmailDoor DropInsertsMailMobileSearchSocialTelephoneTVCommunitiesB2B CouncilCustomer Data CouncilContact Centres CouncilFundraising Working GroupPrint CouncilEmail CouncilVulnerable Consumers Working GroupSocial Media CouncilPrivacy Working GroupDMA Scotland CouncilDMA North CouncilDMA West Council
Show All
X
Start Contributing
My Contributions
X
Search for a member
Filter your results:
Relevance
Date (Newest - Oldest)
Date (Oldest - Newest)
X
Connect to
Company
Are you looking for a...
Show allBrandSupplierAgency.
Choose a business type
Choose a business type
Choose a business type
and/or enter a company name, postcode or keyword
X
Privacy and Cookie Policy
Share
Clip
1. Who We Are: Data and Marketing Association Limited (DMA).
We are the leading UK trade body for the data and marketing industry, led by customer-first principles and a code of ethics.
1) Data and Marketing Association Limited (a company limited by guarantee, registered in England and Wales. Company registration number 2667995).
2) Institute of Data and Marketing Limited (a company registered in England and Wales. Company registration number 02168165), designed to drive the industry forward through fully accredited qualifications that evolve with the demands of consumers, technology and wider society.
3) DMA Talent, which provides a pathway for talent entering the data and marketing industry.
Our registered office address is at DMA House, 70 Margaret Street, London, W1W 8SS.
2. Communications and Updates
When you supply your personal information, you're agreeing to receive regular news and updates about the DMA, events, courses, research, and career programs for the data and marketing industry.
3. Legal Basis
If you would like more information, you can read more about the lawful grounds for processing personal data on the ICO's website.
3.1 Consent. This means that you have agreed to let us process your personal data, in the form of an opt-in or disclaimer, as explained at the point of data collection. You can change your mind at any time.
3.2 Withdrawing consent so we can no longer process your personal data. You can change your mind and withdraw your consent by contacting us at dmaunsubscribe@dma.org.uk, or by writing to us at Legal Department, Data and Marketing Association Limited, 70 Margaret Street, London W1W 8SS.
3.3 Withdrawing consent from receiving marketing communications.
If you'd like to stop receiving marketing communications, you can:
a) Click the unsubscribe/opt-out option in any marketing communications from us.
b) Contact us at dmaunsubscribe@dma.org.uk or write to us at Legal Department, Data and Marketing Association Limited, 70 Margaret Street, London, W1W 8SS.
3.4 Legitimate Interest.
This means we have a legitimate business interest to use your data and we feel that this use is of benefit to you and is something you would expect. We will also offer you the option to opt-out if you choose.
3.5 Contract.
This means we need to process your data in relation to a contract between us and you (eg: your membership contract).
3.6 Legal Obligation.
This means that we have to process the personal data in order to comply with the law.
4. How do we process your personal information?
Purpose Activity
Type of Data
Why we need to process your personal information
Lawful basis for processing
A corporate membership application form at organisation level.
Organisation name.
Postal address.
Telephone number.
Names and contact details email, telephone number, postal address of Compliance Officer.
Names email addresses and passwords of other staff members who wish to be registered with the DMA.
Areas of interests of staff members.
Processing your membership application.
Postal marketing.
Providing Compliance Officer with information relating to compliance obligations under DMA Code.
Providing staff members of corporate organisations with access to the website.
To send email marketing.
Contract.
Legitimate Interest
Contract.
Consent.
Consent.
4.2 Completing an event/ training booking form on the website.
Name.
The name of where you work.
Postal address.
Telephone number (landline and mobile).
Email address.
Job title.
Payment card details, bank account details, billing address.
Dealing with an order or booking.
Internal accounting processes.
Provide you with information relating to your order or booking.
Internal accounting processes.
Contract.
4.3 Completing an individual IDM membership application form.
Name.
Email address.
Job title.
Linked In profile.
Payment card details, bank account details, billing address.
Expected year of graduation for pre-career students only.
Statement that a pre-career student is over 16.
Processing membership application form.
Internal accounting processes.
Providing you with service information relating to your IDM membership.
Contract.
4.4 Individual registration on the website.
Name.
Job title/role.
Email address.
Facebook handle.
Twitter handle.
Biography.
Photograph used as profile image.
Your interests.
Log in details - email address and password.
Providing you with access to the website.
Consent.
4.5 Marketing messages about our products and services.
Email address.
Postal address.
Telephone number (landline or mobile).
Mobile telephone number.
Marketing by email.
Marketing by post.
Marketing by voice calls.
Consent.
Legitimate interest.
Legitimate interest.
Consent.
4.6 Segmentation, analytics, marketing.
Job title.
DMA Region.
The type of organisation you work for.
Your individual profile on the DMA's database.
Your organisation's profile on the DMA's database.
To provide targeted and appropriate marketing messages.
Legitimate interest.
4.7 DMA Talent Programmes.
Name.
Postal address.
Email address.
Telephone number.
Linked In profile.
Interests and activities.
Education.
Work experience.
Views on brands and marketing campaigns.
Details about further education. Gender, race ethnicity, disability, long-term illness, health issues.
Processing your application, evaluation of your application to join a DMA Talent programme, communication whether you have been selected for a DMA talent programme, administering and running the relevant DMA Talent programme.
Equal Opportunities monitoring.
Contract.
Consent.
4.8 Further education institution accreditation form of IDM.
Name.
Job title.
Email address.
Registering the further education institution as an IDM accredited institution
Contract.
4.9 Registration of individual students from IDM accredited institutions.
Name.
Email address.
Telephone number.
Address.
To ensure that students can leave the institution with an IDM qualification.
Consent.
4.10 DMA Awards
Name.
Email address.
Company Name.
Job title.
Address.
Telephone number.
Mobile number.
Entering into the awards, assessing the awards, completing the judging process, communicating about the awards.
Consent.
Contract.
5. Sharing Your Personal Data
5.1 We won't share your personal data with third parties for marketing purposes without your consent.
5.2 We may share your personal data with:
a) Any other trading arm of the DMA, as stated in the intro to this Privacy Notice.
b) Our business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors as part of our relationship with you, and after confirming that they will only process your information on our instruction and while using appropriate security.
c) Our auditors, legal advisers and other professional advisors or service providers.
d) Credit reference agencies, to confirm you are suitable for membership of one of the DMA trading arms.
e) For the purpose of reviewing whether the organisation you're a member of is suitable for membership of one of the DMA trading arms.
5.3 In the case of personal data obtained via our websites:
a) analytics and search engine providers that assist us in monitoring usage of our websites, subject to our cookie notice below.
6. Disclosure of Your Personal Information
6.1 We may share your information with third parties:
a) If we sell or buy assets, in which case we may disclose your personal information to the prospective buyer or seller, subject to the terms of this privacy notice.
b) If the assets of the DMA or any organisations which are part of the DMA are acquired by a third party and members and contacts are one of the transferred assets.
c) If we are legally required to share your personal data, or in order to enforce or apply our contractual terms and conditions with you.
d) To protect the rights, property, and safety of the DMA, our members, and others. This includes sharing your personal information with other organisations for the purposes of fraud protection, credit risk reduction and preventing cybercrime.
7. Transfer of Your Personal Information
If we transfer or store your data outside of the European Economic Areas (the 28 Member States of the European Union plus Iceland, Lichtenstein and Norway), we will take steps to make sure that your data is protected as if it were stored in the UK.
8. Retention Periods
We won't keep your personal data any longer than we need to.
You can take a look at our data retention policy by emailing legaldepartment@dma.org.uk or by writing to us at Legal Department, Data and Marketing Association Limited, 70 Margaret Street, London, W1W 8SS.
We will keep your personal data for as long as we are able to market to you.
If you withdraw your consent, we will keep your details to make sure we don't contact you again for marketing purposes, and for our own legal, regulatory, and accounting purposes.
9. Your Data Matters
We are led by customer-first principles and want to inform you of your personal data rights.
To learn more about your rights and personal data, see the ICO's website 'Your Data Matters'.
If you decide to remove or view the data we hold about you, we may need to confirm your identity. If this is the case, we will let you know, and would need to see some form of ID, like your passport or driving licence.
In order to offer as much clarity as possible, we've supplied links to the ICO website so you can read further into your data rights and what they mean.
a) The right to be informed - you have the right to know what we are collecting and how we are collecting it.
b) Right of access- you have the right to know whether we are processing your personal data, and what we are processing. We will respond within 28 days of receiving your request.
c)
Right to rectification - you have the right to have any incorrect personal data corrected or completed if it is incomplete. We will respond within 28 days of receiving your request.
d)
Right to erasure - this right, often referred to as the right to be forgotten, allows you to ask us to erase personal data where there is no valid reason for us to keep it. We will respond within 28 days of receiving your request.
e)
Right to restrict processing - you have the right to ask us to restrict processing of your data. We will respond within 28 days of receiving your request.
f)
Right to object - you have the right to object to our processing of your personal data based on
(i)
legitimate interests, or for the performance of a task in the public interests/exercise of official authority (including profiling);
(ii)
direct marketing (including profiling); and
(iii) for purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics.
If you have any further questions about the below, please contact us at legaldepartment@dma.org.uk or write to us at Legal Department, Data and Marketing Association Limited,70 Margaret Street, London, W1W 8SS.
If you want to know more about these rights, the Information Commissioner's Office has more guidance on their website, which you can access by clicking here.
10. The right to lodge a complaint to the Information Commissioner's Office
We'd appreciate an opportunity to fix things, but you can complain to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO) byclicking here.
If you contact us at legaldepartment@dma.org.uk, or write to us at Legal Department, Data and Marketing Association Limited, 70 Margaret Street, London, W1W 8SS, we'll try to put things right.
11. Cookies
A cookie is a small piece of information sent by a web server to a web browser, which lets us collect information from the browser. If you'd like to know more about cookies, visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org/.
We use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and to keep track of your browsing patterns - this means that , if you're a registered user, you'll remain logged into your account and your personalised settings will be available, you'll be able to carry out transactions, and you'll have access to your personal account information.
Most browsers will allow you to turn off cookies. If you want to know how to do this please look at the menu on your browser, or look at the instruction on http://www.allaboutcookies.org/.
Unfortunately, turning off cookies may mean our website doesn't retain your personalised settings and may restrict use of the site.
If you would like to change your cookie preferences, please use the "Cookie Settings" option in the website footer.
a) Cookies we use:
Cookie
What it does
How to disable and consequences
_ga
_gat
Google Analytics - Tracks web traffic to the site. Page views & clicks.
We may deliver targeted ads in front of a defined audience that had previously visited the website. So, you may see some ads related to your interest, whilst browsing other websites that accept advertising from the Google Display Network.
Disable in browser settings. No user impact
wow.
Communigator - The cookie tracks company IP's, website history and additional contact info which is provided from a variety of data sources.
Disable in browser settings. No user impact
OptanonConsent, OptanonAlertBox
Onetrust - Cookies used to display and mark acceptance of cookie policy
Site will continue to ask user to accept cookie policy.
PHPSESSID
DMA - Essential to allow the site to recognise user in the system once they have logged-in
Parts of site will not function, no ability to access member only parts of site.
newsletter-subscription-shown
DMA - Used to check if user has been shown the newsletter subscription option in current session.
User will be shown subscription option on each new page, rather than just once whilst on site.
_gcl_au
Google AdSense - User for experimenting with advertisement efficiency across websites using their services
No user impact
_fbp
Facebook Pixel - This cookie will help deliver our advertising to people who have already visited our website when they are on Facebook or a digital platform powered by Facebook Advertising
No user impact
_hjIncludedInSample
HotJar- This cookie is associated with web analytics functionality and services from Hot Jar, a Malta based company. It uniquely identifies a visitor during a single browser session and indicates they are included in an audience sample.
No user impact
_hjid
Hotjar- Cookie to map customer journey on our website to improve user experience.
No user impact
lidc
Linkedin Pixel-This cookie will help deliver our advertising to people who have already visited our website when they are on Linkedin or a digital platform powered by Linkedin Advertising.
No user impact
twll
Twitter Pixel-This cookie will help deliver our advertising to people who have already visited our website when they are on Linkedin or a digital platform powered by Twitter Advertising.
No user impact
12. Third Party Websites and Cookies
Our website may contain links to other websites that are outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Notice.
13. Changes to the Privacy Notice
This privacy notice is regularly reviewed and will be updated when necessary.
Any changes will be published on our Privacy Notice at dma.org.uk (and in the case of major changes, you'll receive an email to clarify the changes).
Any changes will be effective from the publication date, which will also be noted on dma.org.uk.
This notice was last updated June 2020.
The DMA
Data & Marketing Association
Hear more from the DMA
About us
The new DMACouncils and CommitteesDMA member newsfeedJoin us
The CodeInstitute of Data & MarketingDMA Talent
About usContact us
DMA Corporate LearningGreat British CreativityCustomer EngagementResponsible MarketingValue of DataDMA Awards
Contact us
Diversity & InclusionCoronavirus: Advice and HelpEvents & Upcoming webinars
